Konstantinos Pappas

Email: konstantinospapppas@gmail.com
Phone: +34 657124026 +30 6978912292
Address: C. de Atocha 70 28012 Madrid
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kpappas
GitHub: www.github.com/Kostas-Pappas

Summary

I am quantitative researcher with a background in finance and a passion for data science. I love exploring new technologies, reading about financial markets and A.I. related papers. I have been known to rant about hackathons, my Sharpe Ratio, my Trello board being overwhelming and NFL.

If a task entails financial data and involves quantitative modeling and data analysis, I am up for the challenge.

Certifications

- CFA Level 2
- FRM Part 1

Languages

ENGLISH: Professional Proficiency

SPANISH: Advanced User GERMAN: Basic User GREEK: Native Speaker

Other

Military Service - Completed (2016-17)

Conference Presentations:

"The Determinants of option market liquidity" 8th National Conference of the Financial Engineering and Banking Society Athens 19.12.2017

Work Experience

Quantitative Research-ETS Asset Management Factory | Dec 2020-

Conducting quantitative research for equities team. Calibrating investment strategies, developing tools and applications focusing on deep learning and forecasting methods for time series.

Projects worked on VIX forecasting, Quality Factor strategy, Machine Learning Long Short classifier (for Long-Short equities portfolios).

Data Scientist-ETS Asset Management Factory | Jan-Dec 2020

I worked on the analysis of financial statement data to refine our financial ratios database and capture procedures. (preprocessing pipelines scheduler, apis and creating the schemas etc).

Created dashboard for factor expusure and fundamental analysis.

Capital Markets Analyst - ColmexPro | Aug 2018 - April 2019

Monitoring trading room exposure, manage market counterparty risk, and execute trades for clients. I managed to automate emails and excel reports using Bloomberg API, SQL, Python and VBA.

Financial Products Intern - Alphabank S.A. | Feb - May 2018

Analyzing deposit products and transactions pricing using VBA, Access and SQL. Conducting pricing checks and data quality checks of the dat ftabases.

Jr. Auditor - GSDN Consultants S.A. | Jan 2017 - Feb 2018

Main duties involved audit, tax, cost accounting procedures and preparing presentation and reports

Education

Data Science Bootcamp -Ubiqum Code Academy (Barcelona) | May - Nov 2019

I worked on Data Analysis projects using Machine Learning and Deep Learning tools in Python & R and cloud services (AWS, GCP) building and deploying models, dashboards and communicating insights in real world case studies.

Msc Applied Mathematics - University of Athens | 2017 - 2018

Major: Operations Research & Financial Mathematics

Stochastic Mathematics Optimization methods, Computational Methods (MatLab & R), Data Analysis, Derivative pricing

Rsc Rusiness Administration - Athens University of Economic

Bsc Business Administration - Athens University of Economics and

Business | 2010 – 2015

Major : Finance and Accounting

Programming Skills

Python: pandas, numpy, scipy, scikitlearn, tensorflow, pytorch, nltk,

PySpark, dash

R: h2o, mlr, shiny, tidyverse, ggplot2

Data Bases: MySQL, postgreSQL, SQL Server

Other technologies I have worked with: AWS, GCP, GitLab